Vonnegut mss., 1941-2007 LMC 1860
Lilly Library
Vonnegut mss.
1941-2007
Lilly Library
Vonnegut, Kurt
Farber, Donald C.
LMC 1860
49.5 Linear Feet 38 boxes, 1 oversize
The Vonnegut mss., 1941-2007, consists of the papers of novelist Kurt Vonnegut, 1922-2007.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 1997, 2002-2007, 2010
Biographical Note
Kurt Vonnegut, 1922-2007, was an American novelist. He was born in Indianapolis, Indiana on November 11, 1922. He attended Shortridge High School in Indianapolis, where he wrote for the Shortridge High School Echo, one of the few daily high school newspapers in the country. At the urging of his father, Vonnegut attended Cornell University to study chemistry and biology. While at Cornell, Vonnegut worked for the Cornell Daily Sun, even writing his own column. However, before he could complete his degree, he enlisted in the Army. While serving during World War II, Vonnegut survived the firebombing of Dresden as a prisoner of war, an experience that would later influence his novel Slaughterhouse Five (1969). Vonnegut had seven children in all, three from his first marriage to Jane Cox, his three nephews, and a daughter he adopted with his second wife, Jill Krementz. Vonnegut lived in New York with Jill until his death on April 11, 2007.
His first published work was a piece of short fiction "Report on the Barnhouse Effect" which appeared in Collier's, Feb. 1950. Over the years his short stories and articles have appeared in many magazines, but he is best known for his novels, the first of which, Player Piano, was published in 1952. Vonnegut has also written for both the stage and screen, and many of his works have been adapted to film, television and theater.
Scope and Content Note
Much of the general correspondence is from colleagues, friends and fans. Along with major works the Writings section contains screenplays, teleplays, play scripts and many short stories and articles. The Farber files are those of Vonnegut's agent and lawyer Donald C. Farber. They consist of contracts, correspondence and notes concerning translation, performance, and publication rights and permissions. The Publishing Records include royalty reports, contracts and items related to the publication of his works. Miscellaneous items include: awards and trophies, artwork, family related materials, school papers, photographs, and clippings. The additions are materials received since 2002.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. General correspondence; II. Writings; III. Farber files; IV. Publishing records; V. Miscellaneous; VI. Additions; VII. Additions II.
Related Materials
See Vonnegut mss. II, Vonnegut mss. III, and Vonnegut mss. IV, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Authors, American--Correspondence; American Literature--Indiana; Vonnegut, Kurt--Correspondence
- I. General Correspondence (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The general correspondence is mostly with Kurt Vonnegut and is divided into an alphabetical file, rejection letters and a chronological file. Correspondence with Donald C. Farber concerning contracts, translation, performance, and publication rights and permissions are filed in the Farber files. Occasionally letters were left with related writings or in other miscellaneous sections.
  - Arranged alphabetically with occasional letters from Vonnegut filed with correspondent. Mostly with colleagues and friends. Correspondents are: (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
    Anderson, Laurie
    Anderton, David A.
    Balakian, Peter
    Barrio, Raymond
    Batscha, Robert M.
    Boldt, David R. (David Rhys)
    Boorstin, Daniel Joseph
    Bourjaily, Vance Nye
    Boyer, Rick
    Broer, Lawrence R.
    Cadou, E.J. (Eugene J.)
    Cargas, Harry James
    Carmichael, Leland E.
    Chapin, Schuyler
    Coffin, Tristram
    Cooper, Richard
    Cousins, Norman
    Davenport, Basil
    Davidson, Avram
    Deal, Borden
    Dees, Morris
    Degnan, James P. (James Philip)
    Dillon, Diane
    Dobler, Bruce
    Donoso, José
    Dorsen, Norman
    Downey, Thomas J. (Thomas Joseph)
    Eagan, Andrea Boroff
    Eisenhower, Julie Nixon
    Ellison, Harlan
    Engle, Paul Hamilton
    Ewick, Charles Ray
    Failey, Majie Alford
    Farber, Donald C.
    Finch, Nigel
    Flynt, Larry
    Frayn, Michael
    Gettleman, Marvin E.
    Ginzburg, Alexander
    Godwin, Gail
    Goodson, Mark
    Gordimer, Nadine
    Grant, Leonard T. (Leonard Tydings)
    Grass, Günter
    Gray, Stephen
    Harris, Charles B.
    Hart, James David
    Hefner, Christie
    Heimlich, Henry J.
    Hills, L. Rust
    Howie, John Marshall
    Hume, Kathryn
    Irving, John
    Jacobson, Michael F.
    Klinkowitz, Jerome
    Klunder, Barbara
    Laber, Jeri
    Lathem, Edward Connery
    Lawrence, Seymour
    Lewis, Anthony
    Lipson, D. Herbert
    McCullough, Frances Monson
    McLaughlin, David T. (David Thomas)
    Macrae, John
    MacShane, Frank
    Maschler, Thomas Michael
    Meissner, William
    Mellen, Joan
    Mendelson, Anne
    Metzenbaum, Howard M.
    Minetree, Harry
    Moore, Paul
    Nalbantian, Haig R.
    Nault, Clifford A.
    Navasky, Victor S.
    Nicholas, Ralph W.
    Pantzer, Kurt Friedrich
    Penner, Jonathan
    Pieratt, Asa B.
    Pittman, Bruce
    Plimpton, George
    Plumley, William
    Pohl, Frederik
    Randolph, David James
    Rattray, Helen Seldon
    Reed, Peter J.
    Rees, Robert A.
    Reilly, Charles E.
    Roy, G. Ross (George Ross)
    Savary, Louis M.
    Sharp, Eliot Hall
    Shriver, Robert Sargent
    Simon, Daniel
    Simpson, Alan K.
    Sipper, Ralph Bruno
    Slavitt, David R.
    Soifer, Aviam
    Somer, John L.
    Thomas, Marlo
    Thomas, Ronder
    Trotter, Herman
    Tullos, Allen
    Updike, John Hoyer
    Vaughan, Samuel S.
    Wakefield, Dan
    Wästberg, Per Erik
    Webb, Martha G.
    Weide, Robert B.
    Wilson, Donald W.
    Wouk, Herman
    Ziegfeld, Richard Evan
  - 50 rejection slips from various magazines. Mostly printed slips; two or three with notes explaining the rejection, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence includes fan letters, invitations to speak, or regarding various projects, 1955-1978; 1971-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16-43)
    General
    Arranged chronologically.
    See also: Farber files
  - Correspondence, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1-31)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1997; undated (Box 3, Folder 1-15)
- II. Writings (Box 3)
  Organized into the following sections: major works; reviews; short stories and articles; speeches. A few letters to Vonnegut from a publisher or editor are filed with manuscripts.
  - Major Works (Box 3)
    Includes books, play scripts, screenplays, television scripts, and librettos. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Adam. Typescript of screenplay adapted by Robert Bassing, second draft, June 28, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - All the King's Horses (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Screenplay adapted from short story by Tom Cotter (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Teleplay adapted by Stan Daniels from short story (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - The Bagman (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Typescript of synopsis and play script (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Typescript of fragments of play (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Between Time and Timbuktu ...a musical. Book and lyrics by Andrew Barrett, music by Neil Ginsberg (Based on the works of Vonnegut). Typescript of play; program (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Bluebeard (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Typescript, 303 pages, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
      - Photocopy of the final corrected typescript, 319 pages (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Preface to Franklin Library edition (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Breakfast in Bethlehem: A one-act play for children at Christmastime. Four typescript copies, ca. 20p. each; four mimeograph copies, 8p. each. Contains some correspondence. Published as "The First Christmas Morning" in Better Homes and Gardens., Dec. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Breakfast of Champions (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Original title: Goodbye, Blue Monday. Corrected typescript drafts of various sections, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
      - Vonnegut's carbon copy of his final project for the Program in Creative Writing at the University of Iowa, titled:Goodbye, Blue Monday: The Autograph of a Pontiac dealer in the American Middle-West (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      - Typescript. Corrected in autograph, with Vonnegut's original line drawings throughout. Large unpublished section with drawings. Additional typescript, not corrected, perhaps from earlier or later drafts (Box 4, Folder 3-9)
      - First draft of screenplay by Paul Golding and Peter Bergman (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Screenplay by Alan Rudolph. Draft, 9/25/97 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Stageplay adapted by Robert Egan. Typescript (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Cat's Cradle (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Early typescript, carbon copy, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
      - Draft pages (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - A play for seven actors, by Bruce Pribram, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Chemistry Professor. (based on Jekyll and Hyde story). Play, 1978 (see also: Shilling Shocker) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Class of '45. Skit for "peace project." 2 copies (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - D.P.. Carbon typescript of play, with corrections; teleplay (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Deadeye Dick (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Typescript, corrected in autograph. Labeled "Rough ms.", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
      - Typescript with revisions (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
      - Typescript, corrected in autograph. Labeled "Finished ms." (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Typescript (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Photocopy of corrected typescript (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
      - Typescript (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Photocopy of corrected typescript. Labeled "Summer 1981 revise xerox." (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Editorial notes (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Emory Beck. Typescript of play by Robert B. Ruthman and Vonnegut (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Epicac: A one-act comedy (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - (see also: Short Stories: Epicac) Typescript (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Mimeograph. 2 copies (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Euphio Question. Screenplay adapted by Jeffrey Cohen. Outline only, June 15, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Fates Worse than Death (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Typescript, corrected in autograph. Titled: In the Capital of the World: A Collage., 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
      - Typescript, incorporating scenes from the play "Make Up Your Mind," plus Appendix, lightly corrected. Titled: The Hocus Pocus Laundromat: Freethinker Papers (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
      - Typescript photocopy, incorporating scenes from the play "Make Up Your Mind," plus Appendix. Titled: The Hocus Pocus Laundromat: Freethinker Papers (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
      - Typescript. Titled: The Hocus Pocus Laundromat (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
      - Photocopy of corrected typescript, "Complete 1.2.91." (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
      - Photocopy of corrected typescript, January 1991 revised, January 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
      - Photocopy of corrected typescript, 2 copies. Labeled "Complete as of 2.8.91." (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
      - Final typescript. Corrected in autograph (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Box 6, Folder 7-10)
      - Page proofs (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Fortitude: A short film. Typescript; teleplay by Stan Daniels, first draft, several draft pages; photocopy from Playboy Sept. 1968, Oct. 30, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Foster Portfolio. Outline of script, written by Jeremy Hole, May 27, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Galapagos. Introduction to Franklin Library edition (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Girl Pool. Typescript and carbon typescript of play (see also: Short stories and articles: Girl Pool) (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - God Bless you, Mr. Rosewater (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
      - Typescript. Corrected in autograph, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
      - Galley proof. Corrected in autograph. Stamped "Master Proof...", November 25, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Galley proof of God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater (published), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Three typescripts and photocopy of "God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater: A New Musical" by Howard Ashman, Alan Menken, and Dennis Green. Dated:, Apr. 1, 1979; June 4, 1979; Sept. 4, 1979; undated (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
    - Grieve My Lord No More. Typescript of play (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Happy Birthday, Wanda June (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - Typescript, corrected in autograph, of an early draft of the play in novel form. Additional pages of corrected typescript. Titled:The Fur-Lined Bouillon Cup, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
      - Photocopy of early draft of play. Titled: The Fur-Lined Bouillon Cup, or a Woman Is Not an Electric Scoreboard (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Two different typescript versions, corrected in autograph, of an early draft of the play. Titled:Penelope. Additional uncorrected or very lightly corrected typescript drafts. (Box 7, Folder 6-16)
      - Photocopies of Acts 2 and 3, two photographs of production and cover letter from Thomas A. Power of early version of play entitled: Penelope as performed at University of Maine (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Two different typescript versions, corrected in autograph, of an early draft of the play entitled:Something Borrowed. Additional uncorrected or very lightly corrected typescript drafts of various sections (Box 7, Folder 18-25)
      - Typescript photocopy, rev.typescript, rev. typescript, labeled "Final script heavily corrected in autograph; typescript, labeled "Final script lightly corrected in autograph; typescript, labeled "Revised final script with photocopied and original corrections, 8/5/70; 8/24/70; October 12, 1970"; 11/20/70" (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
      - Photocopy of a revised ending, with a photocopy of a letter for Vonnegut to Dusty Hughestypescript of another revised ending, with an original letter from Vonnegut to Don Farber, Apr. 12, 1977; Jan. 8, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Photocopy of French translation (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Heidi Again. Two page synopsis and typescript of play (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - The Helmer Case. Nora. Play. Autograph pages; typescript; and mimeograph (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hey Earth--We're Watching You. Synopsis and proposed cast list for play by Vonnegut and Dick Feldman (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - L'Histoire du Soldat. Music by Igor Stravinsky, libretto by Vonnegut. Six typescripts; page proofs; two related letters; program for performance at Webster University, advertisement for the concert performance at Alice Tully Hall, Lincoln Center, Thursday, 1997; Feb. 24, 1997; May 6, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Hocus Pocus (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
      - Typescript, corrected in autograph. With a second version of chapter twelve., 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14-16)
      - Typescript of the preface to the Franklin Library edition (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - The Hoosier Symphony. Synopsis and various typescript versions of play, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - I Know What I Like. Typescript synopsis of play (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - I'll Go to Sleep in Dresden. Typescript of play (incomplete) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Jailbird (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Several early typescript drafts, entitled:Mary Kathleen O'Looney or Unacceptable Air. mostly rewrites of the beginning chapters, corrected in autograph, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21-23)
      - Early typescript, entitled: Mary Kathleen O'Looney (Or, Fats in a Windstorm). corrected in autograph (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
      - Typescript, Mary Kathleen O'Looney (Or, Fats in a Windstorm). retitled: Jailbird by Vonnegut in autograph (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Final typescript. Corrected in autograph (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
      - Galley proof, photocopy, with autograph corrections. Labeled "Auth set 1st pass...not shooting copy." (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Photocopy with corrections (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - Jonah. Two typescripts of Act I; typescript of fragments of Act II (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Long Walk to Forever. (a short musical). Music and lyrics by Jeff Lazarus (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Make Up Your Mind. Typescripts for different versions of play, three of the typescripts corrected in autograph: four undated, Jan. 1986; Nov. 2, 1987; Summer 1988; Mar. 28, 1989; Apr. 2, 1989; June 28, 1990; 1991 (Box 9, Folder 10-20)
    - The Midlanders. Typescript of play (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Money Talks. Synopsis of play (see also: Short stories...: Money Talks) (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Mother Night. Galley proof of Mother Night; mock-up of trade edition; introduction for 1966 Harper & Row hardback edition. (Box 9, Folder 23-25)
    - Next Door. Second draft of script, adapted by Jeremy Hole, June 15, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Pink Door. Typescript of play (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Player Piano. Galley proof of Player Piano. A few pages missing, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Player Piano. Typescript of play, adapted by Arthur Gerald Brown; outline of novel and synopsis of play by Vonnegut; letters from Brown about the play (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Report on the Barnhouse Effect. Episode 3. Revised mimeograph of television script, Adapted by Claris A. Ross (see also: Short stories: Report on the Barnhouse Effect), Apr. 22, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Requiem. Music by Edgar David Grana, text by Vonnegut. Typescripts and related correspondence and other materials (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Shilling Shocker. Story line for a musical play, based on "Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde" (see also: The Chemistry Professor) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Sirens of Titan. Typescript. Corrected in autograph. Fifteen bundles of rolled-up leaves, with a few pages of typescript drafts. One bundle for Chap. 1-5, 7-9, 11, two for Chap. 6 and 12 [no Chap. 10]. Typescript of a new introduction, 1989., 1959 (Box 25A-25B)
    - Slapstick. Five typescripts of screenplay, lyrics to "Lonesome No More" (Box 10, Folder 9-14)
    - Slaughterhouse-Five (Box 10, Folder 9-14)
      - Corrected typescript drafts of various sections of the novel including three radically different versions of the beginning chapter, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 15-25)
      - Corrected typescript drafts...(cont.), 1969 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
      - Final typescript and two photocopies (Box 11, Folder 5-10)
      - (play). Typescript of synopsis and revised script, dated brochure/order form for performance in Munich; ticket stubs and stagebill for performance in Chicago at the Steppenwolf Theatre; undated clipping of review from the London Financial Times, Dec. 15, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Slice of Life. Synopsis, draft and two typescripts of television script (Box 11, Folder 12-15)
    - Sun Moon Star. (juvenile fiction). Page proof and printer's copy (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Tarkington, Or Adventures in Education. Unpublished. Two typescripts and misc. pages. Contains letter from Vonnegut to Faith, Apr. 23, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17-21)
    - Thumbkin. Typescript of filmscript (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Tom Edison's Shaggy Dog. Script adapted for radio by Bill Zucca (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Tomorrow and tomorrow and tomorrow. Script (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Wampeters, Foma, and Granfalloons. Final draft, made up of typescript pages, magazine clippings, and photocopies, corrected throughout in autograph, with printer's notes in margins, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
    - Welcome to the Monkey House. Script of Act I (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Who Am I This Time?. Two scripts; mimeo script adapted by Aaron Posner, 1977; 1988 (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
    - The Windup Man. Three typescripts of television script (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Synopses of Vonnegut's books (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Untitled filmscript (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - fragment (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Introductions (Box 12)
    - Introduction to story by Frank Conroy for Gentleman's Quarterly (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Reviews (Box 12)
    - Book reviews written by Vonnegut for the following: The Disney Version by Richard Schickel; The Triumph by John Kenneth Galbraith; Unless Peace Comes edited by Nigel Calder (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Short Stories and Articles (Box 12)
    Contains drafts, final typescripts, and related materials. Many accompanying envelopes are covered in Vonnegut's characteristic doodles; some list (in another hand) dates for submission of the story, and, if accepted, the amount paid by various magazines. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - A.W.O.L. (see: Long Walk to Forever) (Box 12)
    - Adam. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 12)
    - Ambitious Sophomore. Saturday Evening Post May 1953 (Box 12)
    - The Amphibians. (see: Unready to Wear) (Box 12)
    - And On Your Left. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Annie. (beginning only) (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - The Ants of Erz Gebirge. (unpublished), (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Any Reasonable Offer. Collier's Jan. 1952 (Box 12)
    - Anybody Can Say Thanks a Million. (see: Guardian of the Person) (Box 12)
    - The Armadillos. (see: The Humbugs) (Box 12)
    - Der Arme Dolmetscher. (see: Das Ganz Arm Dolmetscher) (Box 12)
    - Armageddon in Retrospect. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Atrocity Story. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Bagombo Snuff Box. Cosmopolitan Oct. 1953 (Box 12)
    - Baker's Dozen. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Basic Training (Box 12)
    - Beat Generation: I Hate You. (page 1 only) (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Beeline, Inc. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Between Timid and Timbuktu (Box 12)
    - Bevo. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - The Bleeding Hearts. (see: Robotville and Mr. Caslow) (Box 12)
    - Bockman's Euphoria. (see: The Euphio Question) (Box 12)
    - Bomar. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Bride Doll. (see: The Honor of a Newsboy) (Box 12)
    - The Briefcase. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Brighten Up. (unpublished). Includes Vonnegut letter to Charles Angoff, Aug. 21. 1947 (Box 12)
    - Bugs. (see: The Widow Koradubian) (Box 12)
    - Build Thee More Stately Mansions. (see: More Stately Mansions) (Box 12)
    - Cape Cod Compass. (see: The Cruise of the Jolly Roger) (Box 12)
    - The Cape Cod National Seashore. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Chains. (see: The Genius Club) (Box 12)
    - The Chicago Specialist. (see: The Good Explainer) (Box 12)
    - Christmas Contest. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - City (Box 12)
    - The Commandant's Desk. (unpublished). Includes correspondence with Knox Burger,Collier's 1951 (Box 12)
    - Commuter Ticket. (unpublished) (two pages only) (Box 12)
    - Confido. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Cream of the Eighth Grade. (see: Baker's Dozen) (Box 12)
    - The Cruise on the Jolly Roger. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Custom-Made Bride. Saturday Evening Post Mar. 1953 (Box 12)
    - D.P. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (see also: Major works. D.P.) (Box 12)
    - Damn Your Eyes. (see: Bevo) (Box 12)
    - Damon and Pythias. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Das Ganz Arm Dolmetscher. Atlantic Monthly July 1955 (Box 12)
    - The Debt. (idea only) (Box 12)
    - Deer in the Works. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 12)
    - Desire Under a Hot Tin Streetcar. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Diddle-Diddle Dumpling. (see: Manny) (Box 12)
    - The Divine Portfolio (Box 12)
    - A Dresden Goodnight. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - The Drone King (Box 12)
    - Dry Bones (Box 12)
    - Easy Go. (unpublished) (see also: Desire Under a Hot Tin Streetcar) (Box 12)
    - Ed Luby's Key Club. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Eden. (see: Fubar) (Box 12)
    - Eden by the River (Box 12)
    - Epicac. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (see also: Major Works. Epicac) (Box 12)
    - The Epizootic. (unpublished) (Box 12)
    - Eternal Good Taste. (unpublished) (Box 13)
    - The Euphio Question. (Welcome to the Monkey House) (Box 13)